# Damian Pieczynski

http://pl.linkedin.com/pub/damian-pieczynki/10/b31/7b7 damian.pieczynski@gmail.com

London, United Kingdom skype : dpieczynski twitter : @piecu github: @piecyk

+447754214923, +48725369868

### Personal Statement

I am an experienced, motivated, and reliable software engineer with a passion for creating great products and leading teams, working in a very Agile focused way, practising Scrum, TDD, BDD etc. and any technology that helps me keep ahead of the game. I am interested in developing Web applications, especially in JavaScript - EcmaScript(5,6) technologies(AngularJS, ReactJS, NodeJS). In the nearest future I will focus on functional programming paradigm in Scala, Clojure. Available from february/march 2015.

#### SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, Java, Scala, LATEX, HTML/CSS(3.0)

Software development process: Agile, Pair programming, TDD, BDD

Interested: Scala, Clojure, Docker

Selected Technologies: Angular Js, Lo-Dash, Node Js, j Query, React, Git, SVN, JUnit, Jasmine, Mocha,

GruntJs, Glup, Gradle, Spring, Ruby on Rails, Sass, Less

Tools: Emacs, Jira

Databases: Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Os: Windows; Linux(Arch Linux)

### Career History

# Orbit Developer, Capita Employee Benefits

July 2014 - Present

As a lead AngularJs Expert i'm working on new front-end single page application (SPA), build automation and CI environment for UI part. Creating core reference app for other new projects in company also common ui library. Knowledge sharing sessions, presentations, pair programming. *Technologies:* Agile, TDD, EcmaScript(5,6), AngularJs, Lo-Dash, GruntJs, Sass, NodeJS, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium webdriver, Java, Spring, Tomcat, Redis, ActiveMQ, Gradle

# Software Engineer, Owner, Effective Code

July 2012 - Present

Working on SPA and hybrid mobile application development *Technologies:* Agile, TDD, EcmaScript(5,6), AngulaJs, Cordova, React, Immutable-js, Mori, Gulp, GruntJs, Sass, NodeJS, Mocha, Selenium webdriver, Scala.

# Software Engineer, PGS Software

 $July\ 2012$  -  $June\ 2014$ 

### - Refresh Java web legacy system

2013-01 - 2014-06

As a Software Engineer, I was working on new front-end for legacy J2EE project- remove old JSP server compile pages and transfer to new HTML5 client compile UI, main tasks were: development and lead front-end team, unit and e2e testing, architectural decisions and creating documentation.

Technologies: J2EE, Java SE 1.6, Junit, SVN, GIT, Hibernate, EcmaScript5 - JavaScript, AngularJS, NodeJS, GruntJs, Jasmine, UndrescoreJS, Jenkins, Emacs, Agile, TDD.

# - Apartment finder - startup

2012-07 - 2012-12

As a Software Engineer, I was working on new features for legacy IN (Intelligent Network) platform, main tasks were: development, unit testing, integration testing and creating documentation. Technologies: JEE, Java SE 1.6, Junit, SVN, Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Postgis, Eclispe, Maven, Jenkins, Agile, TDD, EcmaScript5 -JavaScript, BackboneJS, AngularJS.

# Software Engineer - Contract/Remote, Synergia Pro

August 2013 - October 2013

As a Java J2EE/ Front End Consultant, I was working on a team developing and maintaining web based application, writing code and automated tests (frontend and backend) for client from USA (Texas). Technologies: Agile, TDD, Maven, Java 1.6/1.7, Eclipse RAP 2.0, JavaScript, ExtJS, NodeJS, Jasmine, Selenium webdriver.

# Software Engineer, Tieto Poland

June 2010 - June 2012

- Charge@Once-Intelligent Networks Nokia Siemens Network Wroclaw 2012-01 - 2012-06 My main tasks were: development, unit testing, maintenance and creating documentation of Service Control Points stateful and stateless components. Project was set in the international environment: I collaborated with developers and testers from other countries (Germany, India, etc.). Technologies: Agile, TDD, Java, JUnit, Spock, ClearCase, Linux, GIT
- 2010-12 2011-12 - IN (Intelligent Networks) v7.5 - T-mobile Berlin / Tieto Germany As a Software Engineer, I was working on new features for legacy IN platform, main tasks were: development, unit testing, integration testing and creating documentation. Technologies: Agile, Java SE 1.5, Junit, Clear Case, XML, Flex Logic (NSN), Ruby/Bash
- 2010-06 2010-11 - Application Server v2.0 - Nokia Siemens Network Wroclaw Implementation of Java-based Application Server(platform) for comunication with and managing of underlaying Inteligent Network environment. AS is build on top of JAIN SLEE 1.1 standard and its OpenCloud implementation - Rhino platform. My main tasks were: development, unit testing, maintenance and creating documentation.

Technologies: Agile, Java SE 1.6, SVN, Hudson/Sonar, Maven/Ant, CMD/Perl/Bash scripts, XML, Agile.

#### Examples of Projects

Image Shop: https://github.com/piecyk/image-shop

### **EDUCATION**

### Master of Science degree in Software Engineering

February 2013

Wrocaw University of Technology Faculty of Computer Science and Management, Poland

# Courses

# Functional Programming Principles in Scala

September 2014

https://www.coursera.org by Martin Odersky

# **Introduction to Functional Programming**

October 2014

https://www.edx.org by Erik Meijer

### Personal

interest - running, triathlon, photography, music, motorization, traveling, new technologies;

**LATEX**